Finding Aid for the A.M. Rawn Papers LSC.1045
UCLA Library Special Collections
A.M. Rawn papers
circa 1940-1968
UCLA Library Special Collections
Rawn, A.M.
LSC.1045
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
A.M. Rawn (1888-1968) worked for the Los Angeles County Sanitation Districts. He was promoted to chief engineer and general manager of the Los Angeles County Sanitation Districts (1941), and later appointed to California State Water Pollution Board (chairman, 1953-61). The collection consists of manuscripts, letters, photographs, diaries, awards, and printed materials related to A.M. Rawn and his career as chief engineer of the County Sanitation Districts of Los Angeles County. Topics include water pollution and the sewage disposal system of Los Angeles.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. A.M. Rawn, 1969.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9927230313606533
Biography
Rawn was born in 1888; attended school in Toledo, Ohio; worked for the U.S. Bureau of Reclamation; served in the U.S. military during World War I; moved to Los Angeles, 1922; worked for the Los Angeles County Sanitation Districts; promoted to chief engineer and general manager, Los Angeles County Sanitation Districts, 1941; appointed to California State Water Pollution Board, 1953 (chairman, 1953-61); co-wrote report on sewage reclamation plan with Harold Hedger, 1958; died in 1968.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscripts, letters, photographs, diaries, awards, and printed materials related to A.M. Rawn and his career as chief engineer of the County Sanitation Districts of Los Angeles County. Includes 12 working diaries (April 1924-October 1939) and articles by Rawn. Topics include water pollution and the sewage disposal system of Los Angeles. Also includes correspondence from Link Anderson, a neighbor of Rawn's.
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Department of Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
Related Material
Sanitary engineer [oral history transcript] / A.M. Rawn, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1969. Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.
Sanitary engineers -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Rawn, A.M.; Los Angeles County (Calif.). County Sanitation Districts
- Biographical
  - Vita, discharge, commission, diplomas, memberships, awards, etc. (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Staff members CSD, Snake River project, personal. (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - re contractor for Orange County Sanitation District., September-December 1963. (Box 1)
  - re Master Plan Study Sewerage for Ventura County., October 1963-May 1965. (Box 1)
  - re American Sanitary Engineering Intersociety Board., 1957-1958. (Box 1)
  - re Miscellaneous Contracts, Estimates, etc., 1958-1963. (Box 1)
  - re Miscellaneous correspondence with professional colleagues., 1960-1966.; 9 folders. (Box 1)
- Manuscript materials for CSD Narrative. (Box 2)
- Letters of thanks for receipt of CSD Narrative. (Box 2)
- Trip Diary, Itinerary and letters of the Rawn's trip to Scandinavia., 1963 (Box 2)
- Brochure - Dedication of enlarged water renovation plant. Pomona, California., February 25, 1967. (Box 2)
- A.M. Rawn, Fixed and Changing Values in Ocean Disposal of Sewage and Wastes. (Box 2)
- A.M. Rawn and H.C. Hedger, A Report Upon the Potential Reclamation of Sewage..., November 1958. (Box 2)
- Planned Refuse Disposal, A Report. County Sanitation Districts, Los Angeles., September 1955. (Box 2)
- Link Anderson, World travel letters. (Box 2)
  General note
  Anderson was a neighbor of the Rawns who became a millionaire through the operation and ownership of machinery stores. Upon retirement he became a world traveler.
- Working diaries., April 1924-October 1939.; 12 vol. (Box 3)